A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller, Sr. papers FA002
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1804-1896; C; 34.4 Cubic Feet 86 boxes
  - Office, O; 20 Cubic Feet 50 boxes
    - B - Bacon, 63 Pages (Reel 2, Frame 0420, Box 2, Folder 14)
      Personal assistance; Standard Oil Company employees; steamboat franchise; New Jersey Central Railroad; Baptist students' movement; F. T. Gates report; town library; Civil War veteran; job applicants; Sone & Fleming Manufacturing Company; Standard Oil Company of New York; Baptist Church; office space for F. T. Gates; Vassar College scholarship fund; University of Rochester alumni dinner; Anti-Saloon Republican League; Women's Baptist Foreign Missionary Society of the West; schools in China, India, and Japan; proposed Baptist Center in Chicago; copper mines in Michigan.
    - Bacone, A. C., 1880-1892; 99 Pages (Box 2, Folder 15, Reel 2, Frame 0483)
      Indian University, later Bacone University; John D. Rockefeller contributions for student tuitions; needs of the school; conditions in the West.
    - Badu - Baker, 154 Pages (Box 2, Folder 16, Reel 2, Frame 0582)
      Female University, Dallas, Texas; United Society of Christian Endeavor; Frances E. Willard; personal appeals; job applicants; Ohio National Guard; Ladies Home Mission Society; Texas Negro Mission School; Baptist Church; Florida Baptist Convention; State Board of Missions of Florida; Stetson University; Metropolitan Electric Service Company; malfunction of heat at John D. Rockefeller house, 4 West 54th Street; Woman's Branch, New York City Mission and Tract Society; student assistance; Colby Academy; Methodist Episcopal Church; First National Bank of Norwalk, Ohio; John D. Rockefeller housekeeper at Forest Hill; Grand Island Baptist College; Convention of Christian Workers; Union League Club; St. Luke's Hospital appeals; National League for the Protection of American Institutions; real estate; investment offers; F. T. Gates report.
    - Balcom - Ballou, 80 Pages (Box 2, Folder 17, Reel 2, Frame 0736)
      Personal appeals; Western Reserve Historical Society; Botany Club of America; American Association for the Advancement of Science; Denison University; Presbyterian Church; Baptist Social Union; Brown University; Central Railroad Company of New Jersey; Methodist Episcopal Church Missionary Society; insurance agents; shipping of art bought in Europe; real estate; Old Ladies Home; Baptist Church; Colored Baptist Church; Jerry McAuley Cremome Mission; thanks for donation; public library.
    - Bandlow - Barnes, Frances J., 186 Pages (Box 2, Folder 18, Reel 2, Frame 0816)
      Labor lyceum; Central Labor Union, American Federation of Labor; Shurtleff College Art Studio; American Baptist Publication Society; Temple College; Seaman's Christian Association; free kindergarten; Brooklyn Guild; Berkeley Lyceum; construction on 4 West 54th Street house; Baptist Conference for Bible Study; Baptist Congress; American Baptist Home Mission Society; Baptist Quarterly Review; Baptist Social Union of Manhattan Island; Baptist Young Peoples Union of America; Baptist Union Theological Seminary; personal assistance; National Transit Company; public school officials; Standard Oil Company employee killed on job; Riverside Improvement Commission; notice of meetings; trotting horse; personal loan; stationery supplies; St. Luke's hospital; Weikel Run & McElhinney Oil Company; Free Reading Room for Working Boys, Loyal Legion Temperance Society; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU) factionalism and internal politics; personal matters.
    - Barnes, Horace F., 1883-1885; 51 Pages (Reel 3, Frame 0001, Box 3, Folder 19)
      New York City Mission and Tract Society affairs; John D. Rockefeller contributions; lists of contributors; appeal for Mt. Olivet Church, for black freedmen; Charles Pratt memorandum on work of Reverend J. D. Fulton.
    - Barnes, Horace W., 1882-1804; 135 Pages (Reel 3, Frame 0052, Box 3, Folder 20)
      Baptist Missionary Convention of the State of New York; aid to small churches throughout the state; John D. Rockefeller contributions; F. T. Gates comments and suggestions on work; John D. Rockefeller contributions to Church Edifice Fund of the American Baptist Home Mission Society.
    - Barnes, W. - Barnum, 29 Pages (Reel 3, Frame 0187, Box 3, Folder 21)
      Personal assistance; real estate; Bethel Charities; Cleveland Grays, a vigilante militia group; commentary on anarchists in Cleveland; personal matters; Ohio Humane Society; Baptist Church; National Confederate Soldiers' Home in Austin, Texas.
    - Barr - Bayne, 110 Pages (Reel 3, Frame 0216, Box 3, Folder 22)
      Real estate agent; Baptist Church; Castle Garden School for German immigrants; Baptist College for blacks in North Carolina; Pullman Palace Car Company rental for John D. Rockefeller trip; Executive Commission for the Erection of the Monument to Christ; Standard Oil Trust executive; business and friendship; yield and cost statements for oil works; John D. Rockefeller school chum; job applicants; Sunday School Library; Southern Female University; professional baseball; all-purpose liquid beverage and parasite exterminator; Absolute Chemical Company of Akron, Ohio; student assistance; Standard Oil Company employees; Wake Forest University; "Baptist Quarterly Review"; Herter Brothers; orphanage; business loan.
    - Beach - Beecher, 115 Pages (Box 3, Folder 23, Reel 3, Frame 0326)
      Business loan; lumber mill; job applicants; Presbyterian Church; Baptist Church; Standard Oil Company of New York, barrel preparing department; Sunday Breakfast Association; Cleveland Gas Light & Coke Company; concerts; questionnaire on labor and capital; sanitarium in Tennessee; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church.
    - Begges - Benham, 93 Pages (Box 3, Folder 24, Reel 3, Frame 0441)
      Cleveland, Ohio, Board of Trade; job applicants; Edison Illuminating Company of New York; real estate; Young Mens Christian Association (YMCA); Henry Lewis letter on work of YMCA in Oil City; sky light, 4 W. 54th Street; Atlanta Orphan Asylum; Negro orphanage; black Baptist Church; student assistance; University of Chicago; John D. Rockefeller school chum; personal appeals; personal loans; real estate in Maryland on Metropolitan Railroad; "Chicago Horseman"; New York Ophthalmic Hospital; Standard Oil Trust stock dissolution; personal matters.
    - Benjamin, Florence and W. W., 1891-1894; 41 Pages (Box 3, Folder 25, Reel 3, Frame 0534)
      John D. Rockefeller's niece and her husband; gifts; seeks business advice; Standard Oil Company, lubricating department; office procedures; expenses of Forest Hill and Euclid Avenue properties.
    - Bennett - Beveridge, 68 Pages (Box 3, Folder 26, Reel 3, Frame 0575)
      Mission to the Jews; personal loan; Knickerbocker Ice Company; oil barrel dealer; business loan; dressmaker; real estate; Baptist Church; Tuskegee Normal and Industrial Institute; Swiss Benevolent Society of New York; Metropolitan Telephone & Telegraph Company; change of telephone number of Standard Oil Company; paintings for sale.
    - Bevier, M. E. and D., 1886-1894; 42 Pages (Reel 3, Frame 0643, Box 3, Folder 27)
      Cousin on Davison side of family; gifts by John D. Rockefeller; death of Minerva Davison.
    - Bickel, Philipp, 1880-1894; 198 Pages (Reel 3, Frame 0685, Box 4, Folder 28)
      Baptist minister; John D. Rockefeller assistance for work; German Baptist Publication Society; German Baptist Union; personal gifts to Bickel and family; F. T. Gates report; American Baptist Missionary Union.
    - Bickford - Biggar, 104 Pages (Reel 3, Frame 0883, Box 4, Folder 29)
      Baptist Church; American Museum of Natural History; Drew Ladies College; real estate; proposed gun trust; John D. Rockefeller's personal physician; trip to Europe; Huron Street Hospital; Homeopathic Hospital College; personal matters.
    - Biglow - Bitting, C. C., 94 Pages (Box 4, Folder 30, Reel 3, Frame 0987)
      Pullman Palace Car Company rates on private cars for extended trip; medicine for tonsilitis; Baptist Church; Congregational Church; Chesapeake & Ohio Railway Company; Kentucky Horse Breeders' Association; stock market deals, margin accounts; attorney; bankruptcy case of Mary Montgomery; New York Skin and Cancer Hospital; Upper Iowa University Young Mens Christian Association (YMCA); student assistance; University of Chicago; John D. Rockefeller relative; Wellesley College; Woman's Medical College; American Baptist Publication Society; missionary in Turkey; distribution of "Baptist Worker."
    - Bitting, W. C., 1886-1894; 48 Pages (Box 4, Folder 31, Reel 4, Frame 0001)
      Pastor, Mount Morris Baptist Church; appeals; John D. Rockefeller contribution for new building; United Society of Christian Endeavor Convention.
    - Bixley - Blumenthal, 141 Pages (Box 4, Folder 32, Reel 4, Frame 0049)
      Baptist Church; Presbyterian Church; architect; University of Chicago; American Baptist Publication Society; Baptist Missionary Training School; real estate brokers; John D. Rockefeller purchase in Tarrytown (Tower Hill); land investments; bonds; U. S. Senate speech on school bill; American Baptist Education Society group for college work; Continental Oil Company; Colorado Women's College; personal appeals; refrigeration system; John D. Rockefeller cousin; Ooltewah Normal High School; Chase National Bank; Huguenot Seminary in South Africa; temperance work; Beirut Observatory for Syrian Protestant College; American Baptist Home Mission Society; Richmond Institute; Spelman Seminary; church in Mexico City; Bible and Tent Mission; Southern Baptist Theological Seminary; Russian immigrants; loans; book called "The Original Mr. Jacobs," by F. F. Tymayeni, containing attacks on John D. Rockefeller and others.
    - Boalt - Bolton, C. E., 132 Pages (Box 4, Folder 33, Reel 4, Frame 0190)
      Lake Erie Seminary; Baptist Church; University of Chicago; Woman's National Indian Association; Christian Education and National Reform; Wheaton College; American Temperance Union; National Temperance Congress; John D. Rockefeller cousin; business loans; New York Life Insurance Company; personal aid; job applicant; personal matters.
    - Bolton, N. - Bostwick, F. E., 104 Pages (Box 4, Folder 34, Reel 4, Frame 0322)
      Invalids House; job applicants; superintendent at Pocantico Hills; procurement of supplies; Methodist Episcopal Church; personal aid; business loans; Cleveland "Herald"; private detective agency; religious journal proposed in Muscogee, Indian Territory; Riverside Rest Association; home for women discharged from Blackwell's Island; Central Park Speedway; political matters; Baptist Church; trotting horses; Presbyterian Church; Young Mens Christian Association (YMCA); Salvation Army; slum work; Children's Aid Society; Norwegian Relief Society.
    - Bostwick, J. A. - Boswell, J., 63 Pages (Reel 4, Frame 0426, Box 4, Folder 35)
      Standard Oil Trust treasurer and shareholder; payment of John D. Rockefeller salary; trustee of Fifth Avenue Baptist Church; purchase of house for Thomas Armitage; donations; Southern Baptist Theological Seminary; Young Mens Christian Association (YMCA); declined gift to Spelman College; comments on W. H. P. Faunce as new pastor; death of J. A. Bostwick; Baptist Church.
    - Boswell, J. H., 1882-1892; 86 Pages (Reel 4, Frame 0499, Box 4, Folder 36)
      Home of Industry & Refuge for Discharged Convicts; construction of new building; lists of contributors; John D. Rockefeller contributions; F. T. Gates discouraged gifts in report on work and finances of home.
    - Bosworth - Boys' Brigade, 153 Pages (Reel 4, Frame 0585, Box 5, Folder 37)
      Baptist Church; oil lands; John D. Rockefeller's aunt; Charity Organization Society investigation; Rosa Bonheur painting at Chicago Exposition; New York Evening Law School; temperance work; personal loans; University of Michigan Students Christian Association; personal aid; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU); job applicant; congregational Church; steel tubing invention; Bowery Mission; Howard Mission and Home for Little Wanderers; Hiram college; Dorcas Society plans for Invalids Home; New York Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor; Southern Baptist Theological Seminary; Young Mens Christian Association (YMCA); Edward Judson trip to Yellowstone Park; defense of John D. Rockefeller against attackes; S. C. T. Dodd pamphlet on "Combinations; Their Uses and Abuses"; University of Chicago; L. A. Crandall; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; personal matters; John D. Rockefeller donations; Tropical Fruit & Vegetable Company; orange and lemon groves in Florida; Idlewild Fruit Company; consumer cooperative; Cooperative Alliance Limited; Boynton Bicycle Railway Company; Boys' Brigade; F. T. Gates report; Protestant military youth organization and summer camp.
    - Brace - Brayton, 177 Pages (Box 5, Folder 38, Reel 4, Folder 0738)
      Children's Aid Society; University of New Hampshire; farm lands; personal loans; horse shoeing at Forest Hill; Boys Loyal Legion; student assistance; Oberlin College; painting by Joshua Reynolds on display at Young Mens Christian Association (YMCA); job applicants; Dental College; Franklin College; real estate; cousin of John D. Rockefeller; consulting engineer; proposes shipping grain by pipeline; would sell short railroad stocks; Uinta Stock Farm; good mare for sale; Rye Seminary; Congregational Church; Young Mens Christian Association (YMCA); University of Pennsylvania; proposed Chair of Christian Ethics for G. D. Boardman; Baptist Church; New York Chorus society; sailors rest in Bremerhaven, Germany; personal appeals; family dispute; Montana State Prison inmate; temperance meetings led by John D. Rockefeller.
    - Breed - Bristow, 136 Pages (Reel 4, Frame 0915, Box 5, Folder 39)
      Baptist ministry students; public library; piano manufacturer; business loans; National Transit Company; Standard Oil Trust executive; proposed consolidation of oil production in Ohio; pipelines; European trip; stock purchase; carriage builders; personal appeals; Richmond & Danville Railroad Company; Richmond & West Point Terminal Railway & Warehouse Company; car trust certificates; parlors, reading rooms, and gymnasium for young men; real estate; Rockford Seminary; Rochester University alumni dinner; Baptist Church; John D. Rockefeller contribution; Rochester Theological Seminary; John D. Rockefeller's brother-in-law; Standard Oil Company, department of supplies; supervised improvements to John D. Rockefeller real estate; purchase of Standard Oil Trust certificates; youth magazine; Fifth Avenue Baptist Church; advice for John D. Rockefeller on various appeals; Wisconsin Central Railroad; invalidity of 'rebate' life insurance; composer.
    - Broaddus - Brother, 146 Pages (Reel 5, Frame 0001, Box 5, Folder 40)
      Student assistance; Hollins Institute in Virginia; Southern Baptist Theological Seminary; John D. Rockefeller contributions; race relations; W. R. Harper's beliefs; W. W. Boyd's liberalism; distribution of S. C. T. Dodd pamphlet on trusts; Standard Oil Trust stockholdings; Chess-Carley Company; American Cotton Oil Trust stock; Baptist Church; Young Men's Library Association; Standard Oil Company clerk; press relations; Equitable Life Assurance Society; personal appeals; Richmond & Danville Railroad Company trust notes; reorganization of East Tennessee, Virginia & Georgia Railroad Company; Standard Oil executive; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU); proposal for rock granite asphalt pavement; business loans; inventor of new coal stove; shipbuilder offers interest in ship; architect offers services; Burnham Industrial Farm.
    - Brotherton, H., 1885-1894; 48 Pages (Reel 5, Frame 0147, Box 5, Folder 41)
      Minister; did mission work in slub area; appeals; John D. Rockefeller contributions; thank-yous.
    - Brouner - Browning, 145 Pages (Reel 5, Frame 0195, Box 5, Folder 42)
      St. Luke's Hospital; nurserymen; purchase of trees; Brown University; Baptist Sanitarium; real estate; African Methodist Episcopal Church; Keystone Academy; horse for sale; mission work; Baptist Church; Young Mens Christian Association (YMCA); Irish Baptist Home Mission; Cleveland Arcade; New York Port Society; New York Ophthalmic Hospital; Columbus-Americus Institute for Normal Training of Colored Students; Southwest Georgia Baptist Theological Seminary; American Red Cross; work of Clara Barton; F. T. Gates letters; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church Sunday School; Episcopal Church; aid to write "Lives of the Most Notes Colored Women of the Age"; Muskokee Evangel Mission & Baptist School; Colored Congregational Church; horse trainer from Ohio; personal appeals; Browning School; John D. Rockefeller's and William Rockefeller's children.
    - Bruce - Budge, 92 Pages (Reel 5, Frame 0340, Box 5, Folder 43)
      Personal appeals; musical student; Baptist Church; Afro-American correspondent for "The Gazette," seeks loan to buy newspaper; student assistance; trotting horse state legislation; Central Park drive; Cleveland Philharmonic Orchestra; notice of annual meeting; Cleveland Park Bill; Dakota University, Mitchell, South Dakota; cousin of John D. Rockefeller; "History of the Baptists," by Thomas Armitage; E. D. Rockefeller (John D. Rockefeller's mother); H. K. Enos & Company; Manhattan Dispensary and Hospital; Episcopal Church.
    - Buel, A. P., 1885-1893; 87 Pages (Reel 5, Frame 0432, Box 5, Folder 44)
      Acted as John D. Rockefeller agent in personal giving; associate minister, Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; selection process for new pastor; Eliza Jennings Home for Incurables; invested money with John D. Rockefeller.
    - Buell - Bunting, 132 Pages (Reel 5, Frame 0519, Box 6, Folder 45)
      Baptist Church; Mutual Life Assurance Company of Worcester; West Indies missionary; Atlanta University; education of blacks; Great Lakes Missionary; Bethel Ship; New York Christian Home for Intemperate Men; treatment of John McPheleny at Ward's Island mental hospital (John D. Rockefeller servant); F. T. Gates report.
    - Burbage - Burrill, 202 Pages (Reel 5, Frame 0651, Box 6, Folder 46)
      Baptist Church; life insurance; real estate; Alfred University; Garfield Club; Republican Party; personal appeals; monument to Moses Cleveland; job applicant; newspaper interview request; Grande Ligne Mission, Canada; Cleveland Art School; School of Design for Women; loan of painting for art exhibit; Southwest Baptist College for Both Sexes; Baptist Home; Baylor University; American Baptist Missionary Union; Baptist University in Kansas; Working Women's Society; American Institute of Hebrew at Chicago Theological Seminary; work of W. R. Harper; business loans; hot-air balloon.
    - Burroughs - Byrne, 180 Pages (Box 6, Folder 47, Reel 5, Frame 0853)
      Baptist Church; hardware merchants; Southern Baptist Conference; American Baptist Education Society; National Civil Service Reform League; Brooklyn Women's Homeopathic Hospital & Dispensary; status of women physicians; Lake Erie Seminary; Standard Oil Company agent; personal loans; Denison University; student assistance; Standard Oil Company of Indiana chemist; University of chicago; job applicants; Central Friendly Inn; school and missionary work; John D. Rockefeller relatives; trotting horses; Vassar College; Bush & Denslow Manufacturing Company; Atlantic Manufacturing Company; auction of George Washington relics and manuscripts and Martha Washington's bible; Adelbert College of Western Reserve University; Florence, Italy, seminary; Standard Oil Trust executive; National Transit Company; pipeline business; Tidewater Pipe Company; competition; production statistics; Natural Gas Trust; financial matters; refined petroleum market; Colored Mission; Food and Health Exposition; Industrial Education Association; Western Reserve University Medical School and Dental School; New York University; notice of parlor meeting; work of Sue Thresher as missionary in New Mexico; Leather Manufacturers National Bank; job reference; American Fine Arts Society; Baptist Home; anti-masonic publication; Columbia College; Cedar Valley Seminary; Imperial Life Insurance Company; Oneida Publishing Company; poem by Nella Brown Pond; Ohio Board of State Charities; National Prison Association; St. Mary's Aid Association.
    - Cadman - Campbell, Fannie F., 136 Pages (Box 6, Folder 48, Reel 6, Frame 0001)
      Society of the American Institute of Hebrew (Publication Society); Pennsylvania Railroad Department Young Mens Christian Association (YMCA); Cleveland Hospital for Women & Children; Indian University (later Bacone University); Muskogee Evangel Mission; investment offers; Colfax College; personal loans; black man suing railroad over race discrimination; personal appeals; Baptist Church; Baptist Missionary convention of the State of New York; mission for Jews; woman's college; invitation to stakes race; Grand Army of the Republic; Day Nursery and Free Kindergarten Association.
    - Campbell, G. M. (Mrs.) - Carroll, 130 Pages (Box 6, Folder 49, Reel 6, Frame 0137)
      Personal aid; Baptist Church; Amity College; prohibition newspaper; Episcopal Church; Catholic Church; Illustrated Christian Weekly; Temperance Mission; Methodist Episcopal Church; Republican meeting (to meet John S. Wise of Virginia); Bohemian American National Committee to endow Slavonic Choir; appeal; Vassar college; Chess Carley Company; Louisville & Nashville Railroad Company stock; painting loan to Louisville Exposition; job applicant; Oratorio and Symphony Societies (Carnegie Hall); American Temperance Union; Equitable Life Assurance Society; appeal to sell policy therefore get commission and financial aid; Tontine or endowment plan; Baptist Young Peoples Union of North America; American Steel Barge Company; Northwest Equipment Company; real estate; architects; Home for Incurables & Consumptives; Republican National Convention; oil lands in Pennsylvania; telegrapher at Forest Hill.
    - Carson - Carvell, 77 Pages (Box 6, Folder 50, Reel 6, Frame 0267)
      Real estate; mission work with Chinese immigrants; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church.
    - Carver - Cauldwell, 55 Pages (Box 6, Folder 51, Reel 6, Frame 0344)
      Baptist Church; Catholic Church; Standard Oil Trust, office of J. A. Bostwick; real estate matters; Tarrytown water supply; Lake Shore & Michigan Southern Railway Company; New York College for the Training of Teachers; Industrial Education Association; job applicants; gardener; attorney; University of Chicago; Pennsylvania Railroad; temperance; Dorcas Society; Fifth Avenue Veterinary Institute; certifies soundness of John D. Rockefeller's horses.
    - Cauldwell Family (Charles, Elizabeth, and William), 1885-1894; 91 Pages (Box 7, Folder 52, Reel 6, Frame 0399)
      New York Sabbath Committee; advised John D. Rockefeller on various appeals; Mt. Olivet Colored Church; Lexington Avenue Church; work of Augusta Carto with Chinese immigrants; Charity Organization Society; Negro Baptist Church in Harlem; New York City Mission and Tract Society; boarding houses; Ladies Christian Union; John D. Rockefeller contributions.
    - Caulk - Chase, John R., 182 Pages (Box 7, Folder 53, Reel 6, Frame 0490)